SAM LAXTON

70 Pinfold Lane, Cheslyn Hay, Walsall, WS6 7NY

07584098704

lacko 6789@hotmail.co.uk

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I have recently graduated with an A grade from the University of Birmingham Coding Boot Camp while also being employed full time. This 24-week program took place after work hours and gave me a total of 1 year of experience of many different technologies which included React, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, Bookshelf.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Java, Command Line & Git. We were also required to participate in mini projects with peers from my class.

My GitHub Account Link

Professional Portfolio Link

Favorite projects completed:

- Filmapedia (Mini Project 1) A web app that showcases information about any filmed searched. The web app demonstrates my ability to use a Javascript, CSS & Bulma Framework. Using a GET method to retrieve information using application programming interface (API).
- ORM-E-Commerce-Back-End This project was to create routes to send data to the back end and allow us to update, delete and add to the backend. The web app demonstrates the ability to use JavaScript, Node.js & Sequileze. This is good practice on how to get the front end to talk to the backend when transferring data.
- SQL Employee Tracker This project was build to demonstrate my ability of using node is, mysgl2, and console table. Using all of these together has allowed me to explore different avenues within the backend.
- README.md Generator This web application is a README.md generator, this is used to create a high-quality README. I have used the inquirer package, node is & JavaScript which has allowed me to use questions as prompts. I have then used the answers to the questions to populate the README.md.

My current profession is a Doors and Windows Test Engineer at Element Materials Technology based in Wednesbury. I have 6 years' experience of testing to several different BSI written standards. I write up test reports to allow the client to file for certification, helping them with several different certification bodies such as BM Trada and CertiSecure. I spend a lot of time with customers and giving them the best experience with testing.

MY GOALS

I'm looking for a Junior Web Development position within a supportive team at a software focused organization, which would allow me to me part of a products development cycle and help me grow into a well-rounded, high-performing software engineer.

WORK HISTORY

Doors & Windows Test Engineer 05/2017 to Current Wednesbury, Birmingham

- Working with technical documents such as PAS24 & BS6375-1.
- Managing clients testing and certification needs.
- Training up new and existing test engineers in test standards and which I have over 5 years' experience in.
- Strong eye for detail when reporting and documenting testing.
- Designing new test sheets with updated standard requirements such as EN1191.
- Instrumental in redesigning several EN1191 rigs for a cleaner and easier finish to allow for smoother transitioning when changing for new testing and samples.

Research & Development Apprentice 09/2015 to 05/2017 **Dudley, Birmingham**

- BTEC completed in 2017 which gave me a Level 3 in Advanced Engineering.
- Completing various tasks to help push the team in the right direction, such as using PLC's to control different spray methods.
- Creating a new working machine from scratch with the manufacturing team.
- Worked along side a team of engineers who were constantly innovating and looking for new ways to streamline different products.

EDUCATION

UG Aff Coding Boot Camp Web Development, 09/2022 - 03/2023

University of Birmingham

Grade A

Level 3 Extended Engineer Diploma: Research & Development

Apprentice, 08/2017

EEF Technology Centre

PASS

BTEC Level 3 Sport, 05/2017

Black Country University Technical College

Merit

OCR: Principle Learning in Engineering Level 3, 05/2017

Black Country University Technical College

Grade C

GCSE, Various Subjects: 05/2013

Cheslyn Hay Sport & Community High School

GCSE - Mathematics (B)

GCSE - English Literature (C)

GCSE - English Language (C)

BTEC - Sport (Distinction*)

BTEC - Applied Science (Merit)

GCSE - Design & Technology (C)

GCSE - History (D)

ONAT - ICT (Pass)

GCSE - Religious Studies (B)

SKILLS

- · Analytical thinker.
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, Bookshelf.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Java, Command Line & Git.
- Working in teams to create functional applications.
- Preparation of final certification reports and with final signature.
- Fork Lift & MWEP Driver.

- Supportive co-worker, supporting and assisting colleagues with learning new tests or help with certification and clients.
- Confident communicator and able to explain complex standard procedures to client.

LINKS & INTERESTS

- · Walks through nature trails, Gym, Football
- Learning new technologies.
- Listening & producing DJ sets in spare time
- Playing some local gigs for friends and events
- · Reading non-fiction books